<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lilingkai.github.io</title>
   
   <link>http://lilingkai.github.io/</link>
   <description>Developer, Musician, & Film Enthusiast</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> Kevin Li</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>First Post - Goals</title>
	  <link>//first-post-goals</link>
	  <author>Kevin Li</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//first-post-goals</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>With fall quarter officially over, I finally found the time to get this site up and make it look decent (I hope). For my first post, I just wanted to type out what I hope this website/blog can be:</p>

<ul>
<li>A Personal Website

<ul>
<li>Since I am a computer science student, I should probably have one of these right? Something about demonstrating my capabilities and what not. Thus, I&#39;ll have another link to my resume and my github. </li>
</ul></li>
<li>A Creative Writing Space 

<ul>
<li>In the style of a blog. A blog about what you might ask? I&#39;m not quite sure yet. I could post something about my life, a short story, advice on various topics, my opinion of current events, anything really. My mind can&#39;t seem to settle on one niche topic, so for now this blog will remain very open. </li>
</ul></li>
<li>A Film Journal

<ul>
<li>I really like film. I like film so much that as I type this, I&#39;m still considering whether I should switch to a Radio, TV, Film (RTVF) major. I&#39;ll be posting my reviews of films I watch in the future, and maybe write some film related essays/guides.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<p>Hopefully I&#39;ll be posting here often; my last wordpress blog has been dormant for a few years now. To prevent this site from suffering the same fate, I&#39;m making it my goal is to post at least once a week, starting with the new year. Looking forward to a new blogging adventure! Stay tuned for more later. </p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
