<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Website Update on Kevin Li</title>
    <link>https://lilingkai.github.io/categories/website-update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Website Update on Kevin Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lilingkai.github.io/categories/website-update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Website Update</title>
      <link>https://lilingkai.github.io/2016/12/another-website-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lilingkai.github.io/2016/12/another-website-update/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;With my return home from another gruelling quarter of classes, I&amp;rsquo;ve revamped the look of my website once more. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick &amp;ldquo;patch notes&amp;rdquo; if you will:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;visual-update&#34;&gt;Visual Update&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first website update, my main concerns were converting my Ruby and Jekyll website/blog into a Hugo website. I decided upon a simpler and cleaner theme: &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/redlounge/&#34;&gt;Redlounge&lt;/a&gt;. However, I decided that it was perhaps too simple for my taste, and decided to look to implement something that was still simple and clean, but also beautiful. I stumbled across &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-tranquilpeak-theme/&#34;&gt;Tranquilpeak&lt;/a&gt; and immediately cloned the theme from GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1481776868/showcase_fypobq.png&#34; alt=&#34;Tranquilpeak&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with Hugo and Markdown, changing themes is relatively simple. Essentially everything is laid out for you in the themes&amp;rsquo; config file. After customizing the config.toml file the way I wanted it, I just had to update all my posts&amp;rsquo; headers with YAML formatting, and then it was all ready to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-s-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I&amp;rsquo;d love to write blog posts and reviews more often, but as a 4th year undergrad, schoolwork and job search tend to take up a lot of my time. At this moment, I&amp;rsquo;ve not decided on any set plan, but I can promise that I will be writing a reflection of 2016 and posting that here before the end of the year. There, now hold me to it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-changes-updates&#34;&gt;Other Changes &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;removed some more outdated/irrelevant posts, including some older film reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated my resume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;moved images to be loaded from a cloud rather than from source, speeding up webpage-loading time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Update</title>
      <link>https://lilingkai.github.io/2016/08/website-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lilingkai.github.io/2016/08/website-update/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been awhile since I updated my site, so when I came back, I decided to re-design/re-build it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;switch-to-hugo&#34;&gt;Switch to Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly due to the unfortunate fact that my last laptop died and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go through the pain of configuring Ruby and Jekyll on a new Windows machine. And it&amp;rsquo;s good to dust off and freshen up things every once in awhile. After a quick research session, I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a static website generator built with the ever-rising Go language. Hugo is pretty easy to pick up, very fast, and nice and compatible for all OS&amp;rsquo;s (unlike Ruby and Jekyll).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-look&#34;&gt;New Look&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a new static generator selected, I wanted to find a new theme. My old theme (Casper for Ghost) was fine, but I wanted something simpler and cleaner. I ended up choosing this &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/redlounge/&#34;&gt;Redlounge&lt;/a&gt; theme, which has been pretty customizable. The documentation for it doesn&amp;rsquo;t explain everything, but once you get comfortable with how Hugo works, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty simple to figure out how to get things to look just the way you want them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-changes-updates&#34;&gt;Other Changes &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;removed some outdated/irrelevant posts and pages, including some older film reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated my resume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated images to fit CSS layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>