<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin Li</title>
    <link>http://kevinwli.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kevin Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://kevinwli.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter: 3 Things I Learned</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2017-03-26-winter-3-things-I-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2017-03-26-winter-3-things-I-learned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spring break is almost over, and I’ve spent half of it alone in my apartment, cleaning, sleeping, and relaxing. While it’s not most people’s idea of a senior year spring break, it’s given me time to think about what’s happened to me so far this year. 2017 certainly came ready to fight, and I leave winter quarter with a fair share of bruises. It’s been a season of sadness and rejection, but it’s also been a season of tremendous growth and change, and I wanted to share a little bit about it. Here are 3 things I learned this quarter:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-how-to-disciple-others-when-i-don-t-always-have-the-right-answers-br-br&#34;&gt;1. How to disciple others when I don’t always have the right answers &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was asked during winter break if I was interested in discipling someone I was hesitant. “I’m just trying to figure things out for myself&amp;hellip; How can I possibly help guide others?” This thought has prevented me from applying for leadership roles in the past; I just didn’t think I was ready to lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I ended up saying yes, because while discipleship was something new to me, it was in a lot of ways, very familiar to me. As the eldest child of the family with two younger siblings, I’ve felt the pressure of being a good role-model since the day my brother was born. In the past, I’ve given young aspiring musicians lessons. And surprisingly, I’ve found that a lot of people come to me looking for relationship advice (this is unfortunately not a joke).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as I’ve gotten to know my disciples throughout winter quarter, I learned that discipleship isn’t about leading, walking in front, and telling them what’s right/wrong in life; it’s really about walking along side of them, listening, and growing together in this adventure called life, and it’s been one of the best experiences of my senior year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-how-to-be-alone-again-br-br&#34;&gt;2. How to be “alone” (again) &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or rather “how to deal with feelings of loneliness, bitterness, and anger”. Losing a relationship and seeing that connection collapse is often painful, and while it’s something that unfortunately happened to me, I’ve re-learned how to deal with these emotions and emerged from the experience with my head held high and ultimately much better than where I started a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do we deal with these ugly emotions? It’s a bit different for everyone; we all have our coping mechanisms. Some like to bottle up their emotions and put it on a high shelf, leaving it to fester until it explodes, potentially harming others around them. Others twist on the cap halfway, only letting a little bit of emotions come out at each time. And then there are people like me, who smash the bottle of emotions against the wall and face everything head on. I wouldn’t recommend the last one if you don’t have supportive friends or community to catch you when you fall. I call it my “safety net”. Without my safety net’s outpouring support, I’m not sure I would’ve recovered as quickly as I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People can surprise you when you’re grieving. A lot of people I wouldn’t expect came up to me and let me know they were here for me, available to talk, pray for me, etc. Honestly, it was quite touching, and it usually resulted in me excusing myself to the bathroom to wipe away the forming tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what I’m trying to say is I learned that I’m never truly alone, and that I’m so grateful for everyone who lifted me up this quarter. I know it’s cheesy, but y’all are a big part of the reason I’m doing well today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-how-to-let-go-of-what-i-cannot-control-br-br&#34;&gt;3. How to let go of what I cannot control &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t that long ago I would’ve been stressed out about not having an internship lined up for the summer by now, or that I’d be obsessing over what went wrong in my last interview when I thought everything went right. It wasn’t long ago that I couldn’t sleep at night because I was poring over every detail of my last relationship, trying to figure out what I could’ve done better. Yet today, I feel at peace with where I am, because I’ve learned to not worry about what I can’t control. It sounds so simple in practice, but for a people who are pseudo-perfectionists like myself, this can be difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not exactly sure what I did to finally feel this peace. Perhaps it was the meditative silence and solitude retreats I had almost every morning that calmed my mind. Perhaps it was using my new piano keyboard as a therapeutic tool. Perhaps it’s the encouragement I get from my friends, colleagues, and family that takes off a bit of the pressure. It was probably all three and more. It’s a realization that as much as we want to be in control, God is the one in control, and if we can’t even trust Him with something like our summer plans, how in the world are we going to trust Him with our salvation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I choose not to worry and to put my trust in Him. This doesn’t excuse me from trying my best in everything I do, but at least at the end of the day, I’ll have spent my energy in productive ways, and sleep easy knowing that He is good and that everything will be ok.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Update: Version 0.3</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2017-03-17-website-update-version0dot3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2017-03-17-website-update-version0dot3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another quarter of classes has come and passed, and yet another update has gone live. Take a look at the shortlist of changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New URL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Theme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Portfolio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;kevinwli-com&#34;&gt;kevinwli.com&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, there is a new url now. No offense Github, but I was getting sick of the &amp;ldquo;lilingkai.github.io&amp;rdquo;, so I went on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.namecheap.com/&#34;&gt;Namecheap&lt;/a&gt; in search for a custom domain name. Unfortunately, kevinli.com is taken and the user is selling it for a very expensive price ($500 minimum offer!), so I elected to go with kevinwli.com for a more reasonable $10/year. Setting up the custom domain was a piece of cake as both Github Pages and Namecheap had step by step tutorials that were easy to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;strata-theme&#34;&gt;Strata Theme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old Tranquilpeak theme wasn&amp;rsquo;t compatible with Hugo 0.19, and I wanted to have a nice way of displaying all the noteworthy projects I&amp;rsquo;ve done, so I figured it was time for another theme update. &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/strata/&#34;&gt;Strata&lt;/a&gt; had the closest thing to what I was looking for, except the default template was set up for showing off photography portfolios. After changing fonts and some colors, I repurposed the picture portfolio boxes to link directly to my projects. Which leads into the next point&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-portfolio&#34;&gt;Project Portfolio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, on the home page, there is now a section that displays my projects. Please feel free to check those out. I&amp;rsquo;ve added some pretty cool ones, particularly &lt;a href=&#34;http://harmoniousmonk.info/&#34;&gt;Harmonious Monk&lt;/a&gt;, which is an automatic jazz harmonizer that I just made this past quarter with two teammates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-s-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can expect a quarterly report of sorts coming within the next few days (by the end of spring break at the latest).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Best Moments of 2016</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2016-12-31-my-best-moments-of-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2016-12-31-my-best-moments-of-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new year is just a few hours away, and it seems that 2016 will be forever seen as quite the poop stain on the scrolls of history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem fair to the good parts of 2016, and it&amp;rsquo;s no fun to be bombarded with bad news all the time. So instead of talking about the US election, Brexit, terrorist attacks, celebrity deaths, etc. I wanted to briefly share four of my favorite moments from this year. While reading about it might not be as interesting or uplifting to you as it was for me writing it, I hope that you can look back on your own year and see that maybe 2016 wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;winter&#34;&gt;WINTER&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;january-17-meeting-natalie&#34;&gt;January 17: Meeting Natalie&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1483227922/IMG_0215_grthgq.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Natalie&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, this year was full of new friends and new experiences, and no other day better represents this than January 17th. I had just finished my first project for my film class, and I had a great time filming with some of my friends who graciously agreed to be my actors. After treating them to a fun dinner, I remembered that my other friend was holding her birthday party that night. While I wasn’t planning on going, I’m very glad I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the birthday party, I reconnected with many friends I hadn’t seen in a while, and I also met many new faces. Many of these new faces would go on to become my friends, but one face in particular caught my attention that night. You know those movie scenes where the guy sees the girl for the first time and he’s already in love? I always thought that was just a bunch of unrealistic crap, but I found myself in a similar movie scene that night when I met Natalie. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know it then, but in a little more than a month, this girl would be my girlfriend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;spring&#34;&gt;SPRING&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;may-29-my-brother-s-graduation&#34;&gt;May 29: My Brother’s Graduation&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1483224613/IMG_1400_vsefej.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Michael&#39;s Graduation&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;
As the title suggests, my brother&amp;rsquo;s high school graduation was on this day, and it was hard to believe that he was already graduating when it felt like I had just graduated high school not too long ago. I came back home from school for that weekend to see him walk across the stage with a goofy graduation cap on. I didn’t come home alone though; Natalie and two of our good friends came as well to see my great homeland of Iowa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I know what you might be thinking: What is there to do in Iowa anyway? And you’d be mostly right if you thought the answer to that question was “nothing”. But experiences can be greatly enhanced by the people you are with, and this day was no exception. After attending the graduation ceremony and embarrassing my brother as he walked across the stage, my friends and I took a trip up to the Maquoketa Caves and hiked around. We had dinner at this awesome all-you-can-eat fried chicken and shrimp place, and went to the drive-in theatre afterwards to watch X-Men Apocalypse (I don’t recommend the movie by the way). It was the most fun I had in the state of Iowa in recent memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summer&#34;&gt;SUMMER&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;june-10-16-banff&#34;&gt;June 10-16: Banff&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1483224427/IMG_1970_lhdlwj.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Banff&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;
Shortly after the school year ended, I flew out to Banff, Canada to meet up with my family and explore the Canadian Rockies. Banff has been on my &amp;ldquo;bucket list&amp;rdquo; of travel destinations, so I was super excited to experience it. Banff is just as beautiful as everyone says it is, and spending time with family was good after a hard quarter of classes. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a 2017 free pass to all of the Canadian national parks, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be definitely looking for another opportunity to go back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fall&#34;&gt;FALL&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;september-15-18-disney-universal&#34;&gt;September 15-18: Disney &amp;amp; Universal&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1483228147/2016-09-16_11.46.16_exixx8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Disney&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;
(They always seem to be doing construction on that castle&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right before going back to school, Natalie and her brother and I took a trip out to Orlando to visit Disney World’s Magic Kingdom and Universal Studio’s Harry Potter World. Now I’ve been to these places before, but of course, things are different when you’re going with your significant other. The whole experience was pretty surreal, and I loved watching Natalie react to all the cool, wonderful stuff in Harry Potter World and just feel like a little kid again. Plus, it was good to relax and get away from home after an eleven-week internship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;winter-1&#34;&gt;WINTER&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;reflection&#34;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1480470080/typewriter_bbq4uv.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Reflection&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;
2016 has been a transformative year for me, and while you could say that technically every year has been transformative, I&amp;rsquo;d say it&amp;rsquo;s doubly true for 2016. I&amp;rsquo;ve made so many new friends, gotten involved with the Christian Asian American community on campus, filmed a documentary and short film, wrote a TV-show script, learned about machine learning and other new technologies, sang in a church choir, and traveled to new and old destinations with fresh eyes. The biggest things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about myself is that I really value strong communities and relationships. I hope that next year I can keep strengthening the communities and relationships I&amp;rsquo;m already a part of, as well as cultivating new ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of next year, I can say that 2017 will be even more transformative: graduating college, becoming a &amp;ldquo;real adult&amp;rdquo;, and finding a job is going to be one helluva ride, and I&amp;rsquo;d be lying if I said I wasn&amp;rsquo;t a little scared. But you bet I&amp;rsquo;ll be ready for whatever is coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy new year everybody. I&amp;rsquo;ll see you on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Update: Version 0.21</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2016-12-14-website-update-version0dot21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2016-12-14-website-update-version0dot21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With my return home from another gruelling quarter of classes, I&amp;rsquo;ve revamped the look of my website once more. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick &amp;ldquo;patch notes&amp;rdquo; if you will:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;visual-update&#34;&gt;Visual Update&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first website update, my main concerns were converting my Ruby and Jekyll website/blog into a Hugo website. I decided upon a simpler and cleaner theme: &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/redlounge/&#34;&gt;Redlounge&lt;/a&gt;. However, I decided that it was perhaps too simple for my taste, and decided to look to implement something that was still simple and clean, but also beautiful. I stumbled across &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-tranquilpeak-theme/&#34;&gt;Tranquilpeak&lt;/a&gt; and immediately cloned the theme from GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;http://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1481776868/showcase_fypobq.png&#39; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with Hugo and Markdown, changing themes is relatively simple. Essentially everything is laid out for you in the theme&amp;rsquo;s config file. After customizing the config.toml file the way I wanted it, I just had to update all my posts&amp;rsquo; headers with YAML formatting, and then it was all ready to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-s-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I&amp;rsquo;d love to write blog posts and reviews more often, but as a 4th year undergrad, schoolwork and job search tend to take up a lot of my time. At this moment, I&amp;rsquo;ve not decided on any set plan, but I can promise that I will be writing a reflection of 2016 and posting that here before the end of the year. There, now hold me to it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-changes-updates&#34;&gt;Other Changes &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;removed some more outdated/irrelevant posts, including some older film reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated my resume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;moved images to be loaded from a cloud rather than from source, speeding up webpage-loading time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Update: Version 0.2</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2016-08-27-website-update-version0dot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2016-08-27-website-update-version0dot2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been awhile since I updated my site, so when I came back, I decided to re-design/re-build it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;switch-to-hugo&#34;&gt;Switch to Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly due to the unfortunate fact that my last laptop died and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go through the pain of configuring Ruby and Jekyll on a new Windows machine. And it&amp;rsquo;s good to dust off and freshen up things every once in awhile. After a quick research session, I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a static website generator built with the ever-rising Go language. Hugo is pretty easy to pick up, very fast, and nice and compatible for all OS&amp;rsquo;s (unlike Ruby and Jekyll).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-look&#34;&gt;New Look&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a new static generator selected, I wanted to find a new theme. My old theme (Casper for Ghost) was fine, but I wanted something simpler and cleaner. I ended up choosing this &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/redlounge/&#34;&gt;Redlounge&lt;/a&gt; theme, which has been pretty customizable. The documentation for it doesn&amp;rsquo;t explain everything, but once you get comfortable with how Hugo works, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty simple to figure out how to get things to look just the way you want them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-changes-updates&#34;&gt;Other Changes &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;removed some outdated/irrelevant posts and pages, including some older film reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated my resume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updated images to fit CSS layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Revenant</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2016-01-08-the-revenant-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2016-01-08-the-revenant-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While it’s not a film I particularly love, I admire “The Revenant” for its beauty, cinematography, and visceral depiction of the wild. This is a film that is meant to be seen on the big screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;http://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1480470086/revenant_pavmbz.jpg&#39; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Revenant” is the survival story of Hugh Glass (Leonardo DiCaprio), a fur trapper who was betrayed by John Fitzgerald (Tom Hardy) and left by his companions for dead after being mauled by a bear. It’s a mesmerizing experience, and Alejandro Iñárritu captures the grizzly beauty of the unforgiving mountains and the cold winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leonardo DiCaprio and Tom Hardy both give great performances, but it’s hard to compare the two. DiCaprio doesn’t have many lines throughout the film, so all of the acting comes from physical action and from the eyes. To portray a man who experiences pain and hardship every step of the journey is certainly not easy, and it’s a haunting performance that makes viewers meditate on the limits of the human body and our drive to survive. Hardy’s character is a bit more nuanced as he has the most dialogue. His American accent is very convincing but sometimes sounds like he has five marbles in his mouth. Not that it really matters anyway, most of the dialogue in the film is not very interesting or cliché.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you don&amp;rsquo;t go see &amp;ldquo;The Revenant&amp;rdquo; for its interesting dialogue (go see &amp;ldquo;The Hateful Eight&amp;rdquo; if you want dialogue); most of the appeal in the film comes from the visuals. However, the luscious pictures start to lose its effect on you as time drags. While the first third of the film will wow most viewers, others might start to feel the length during the middle, and the last third disappoints as it had strange pacing issues and the potential for being interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film also doesn’t establish any substantial emotional connection with the characters. By the end of the film, I couldn’t care less which man would emerge on top. But the film certainly accomplishes its quest to overwhelm our senses with scenes of grit and blood in a wild, beautiful, and dangerous place where humans don’t belong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: Alejandro González Iñárritu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starring: Leonardo DiCaprio, Tom Hardy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015, R, 156 min&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carol</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2016-01-05-carol-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2016-01-05-carol-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am not by any means an expert on the subject of love, but I believe “Carol” is one of the most realistic and intelligent portrayals of love that I’ve seen in film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;http://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1480470082/carol_ct6zsq.jpg&#39; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on Patricia Highsmith’s novel, “The Price of Salt”, “Carol” is a beautiful love story set in 1950’s New York that features two main characters. The first one we meet is Therese (Rooney Mara), a young, doll-like woman in her 20’s who works in the doll-section of the toy store, but aspires to be a photographer. The other is Carol (Cate Blanchett), a socialite, wife, and mother, who enters the toy store looking to buy a doll for her daughter. It’s in this simple store that the two women first meet and begin their relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film does a lot more showing than telling, something that’s all too rare in today’s cinema. Todd Haynes’ restraint creates a romance that doesn’t descend into the land of the hormonal, and it feels a bit more like we’re seeing real people trying to figure out what the other person is thinking and at what level is their relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, that wouldn’t have been possible had it not been for Cate Blanchett and Rooney Mara’s great performances. It&amp;rsquo;s the subtle gestures in their acting that allow us to see how they fall in love. Blanchett’s poise and voice are bewitching, and Mara draws us in with her a mysterious Hepburn-like character, a bit of an alien “flung out of space” as Carol describes her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all shot with careful detail to depict 1950’s America. The sets and costumes with their record players, cars, furniture, clothing, hair, and cigarettes are immaculately presented. Much of the film is shot through windows, as if we are looking through the glass, wondering what we will discover there. You’ll be pleased to find something beautiful and deeply human looking back at you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: Todd Haynes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starring: Cate Blanchett, Rooney Mara&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015, R, 118 min&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hateful Eight</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2016-01-02-the-hateful-eight-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2016-01-02-the-hateful-eight-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quentin Tarantino’s eighth film, “The Hateful Eight”, is some sort of twisted game of Clue in the style of a Western, set ten or so years after the American Civil War. Add a stellar cast and a beautiful original score written by Ennio Morricone and we’ve got ourselves a good movie that’s entertaining as hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;http://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1480470082/hateful-eight_kgqjoq.jpg&#39; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;

This film is very different from other Tarantino films, which featured clear protagonists; the characters in “The Hateful Eight” are more complex and certainly more hateful. We’re not sure who to root for since all of them are untrustworthy, making it all the more exciting to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the film does lack some depth. While “Inglorious” and “Django” were set in significant historical events that gave them a sense of something greater than themselves, “The Hateful Eight” seems to be more of a gruesome celebration of the story itself. Still, it’s an impressive story, even if it might not mean anything in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kurt Russell plays a bounty hunter who is transporting the murderer Daisy (Jennifer Jason Leigh) to her hanging. Along the road, he picks up Major Marquis Warren (Samuel L. Jackson), another bounty hunter, and the new sheriff of the town, played by Walton Goggins. When they find shelter at a cabin, we’re introduced to another set of characters: a mysterious cowboy (Michael Madsen), an Englishman (Tim Roth), the Mexican horse caretaker (Demián Bichir), and the Confederate general (Bruce Dern). As the blizzard descends upon them, the cast is officially trapped inside, and the rest of the plot unfolds in the cozy cabin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pacing of this three hour grandiose film could be described with the metaphor of the boiling frog. For those of you who are unfamiliar, if you place a frog in a pot of cold water and turn the stove on low heat, the water will gradually heat up, and before long, the frog will unresistingly allow itself to be boiled to death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the audience is the frog, then the first chapter of the film is the cold water, aptly set in the wintery Wyoming mountainside. The film takes its sweet time assembling its hateful crew together, and tension grows as the water is starting to heat up.  With all the juicy, Tarantino-style dialogue and excellent performances from Jackson, Goggins, and Leigh (to name a few of the standout performances), you don’t even realize two hours has already passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The water is starting to reach the boiling point as we enter the final chapters of the film, which takes a turn for the grotesquely violent side. If you thought “Inglorious” or “Django” was hard to watch, “The Hateful Eight” is much worse. There are moments so gruesome that your stomach might do a flip or two, and others that are so ridiculous that it’s hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Hateful Eight” is perhaps the funniest and definitely the bloodiest Tarantino film to date, and I look forward to seeing what the genius director/writer decides to make next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: Quentin Tarantino&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starring: Samuel L. Jackson, Kurt Russell, Jennifer Jason Leigh, Walton Goggins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015, R, 187 min&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2015-12-30-joy-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2015-12-30-joy-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the film celebrates strong matriarchal characters and the power of determination, I can’t help but wish “Joy” was better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;http://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1480470084/Joy_g8smuu.jpg&#39; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is David O. Russell’s third film in a row featuring the talented Jennifer Lawrence, but unlike “Silver Lining’s Playbook” and “American Hustle”, “Joy” is a bumpy ride that isn’t always enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film is loosely based on the life of Joy Mangano, inventor of the Miracle Mop and eventual founder of Home Shopping Network (HSN). The key word here is “loosely”, as much of the film is a fictional recount of Joy’s tale from rags to riches, and the name Mangano is never even mentioned. It’s best to review this film as fiction rather than a biopic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jennifer Lawrence does a fine job portraying Joy and makes us care about her and her dreams. It makes scenes with her bloodsucking leech of a family that much harder to watch because each one of them, save for her grandmother and children, seems bent on suffocating her creativity and keeping her in a subservient position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film ultimately suffers from a lack of balance, cohesion, and tonal control. I wasn’t sure whether the film was supposed to be a comedy or drama or both. The scenes that are supposed to be comedic are funny in a feel-bad kind of way since most of them are at the expense of Joy’s happiness. Scenes of despair feel cheapened when they are quickly followed by a scene of triumph. Whether or not these choices were intentional, the end result is the same: a chaotic work that leaves much to be desired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: David O. Russell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starring: Jennifer Lawrence, Robert De Niro, Bradley Cooper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015, PG-13, 124 min&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Force Awakens</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2015-12-18-star-wars-the-force-awakens-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2015-12-18-star-wars-the-force-awakens-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most anticipated movie of the year, &amp;ldquo;Star Wars: The Force Awakens&amp;rdquo;, lives up to all the hype, and J. J. Abrams delivers the best early Christmas present I could ask for.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;http://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1480470079/starwars_sbmgqh.jpg&#39; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seventh installment of the famed franchise arrives three years after George Lucas sold Lucasfilm to Disney. The sale allowed Disney to take control of the story, and they decided to depart from Lucas&amp;rsquo; original outline. Sounds scary I know, but the fandom can rest assured as the Force is apparently strong with Disney, and they&amp;rsquo;ve created a brilliant space opera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like the original trilogy, “The Force Awakens” is a classic good versus bad story, but this time it’s fueled with exciting new characters, Rey (Daisy Ridley), Finn (John Boyega), and Poe (Oscar Isaac) alongside the iconic originals, Han Solo (Harrison Ford), Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher), and Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill). The film takes place three decades after the events of “Return of the Jedi” and the familiar slanted word scroll fills us in with the details of the past thirty years. In short: Luke Skywalker has vanished, and in his absence, the ashes of the old Empire have given birth to The First Order, a new threat to all peaceful systems and planets. It’s a race to see who can find Luke faster; the bad guys need to destroy the last Jedi knight, and the good guys need him to lead their side to victory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abrams tells the story with masterful pacing and balance. From action sequences to character development or sentimental drama to comic relief, the film never misses a beat. The plot is always driving forward, yet it seems to take its time traveling through the magnificent world that has been built, complete with its own eclectic mix of alien species and droids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seamless integration of new and old characters is a true testament to the success of the film. The new characters are never overshadowed by the old, and Ridley and Boyega have great chemistry with Ford, who acts as a sort of father figure while retaining the grumpy and irreverent attitude of Han Solo that fans have come to know and love. It’s safe to say that many viewers will walk out of the theater finding that while Luke, Han, and Leia still hold a special place in their hearts, they&amp;rsquo;ve also made room for the young Rey and Finn (and the adorable droid, BB-8).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the film isn’t perfect, but was perfection ever a feasibility? It certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t possible to please everybody. Some fans might be disappointed with the supposed power of the Dark Side, or the fact that the plot errs on the safe side. But for every &amp;ldquo;wrong&amp;rdquo;, there are ten more things that Abrams gets right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To discuss the film in further detail here would be a crime; just go and experience what the whole world is buzzing about for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: J.J. Abrams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starring: Daisy Ridley, John Boyega, Oscar Isaac, Adam Driver, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Mark Hamill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015, PG-13, 135 min&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kevin&#39;s Film Review Style Guide</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2015-12-13-guide-to-my-film-review-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2015-12-13-guide-to-my-film-review-style/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The basic format of my film reviews consist of 2 parts:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My rating on a 5 star scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A (very) short review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-5-star-rating-system&#34;&gt;The 5 Star Rating System&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system is quite similar to the “Little Man System”, which was conceived by Mick LaSalle, film critic for the San Francisco Chronicle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733&lt;/h3&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;This rating is reserved for what I believe are great examples of film from that genre or time period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733&lt;/h3&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Thumbs up. Definitely good, very enjoyable, and not quite great. People are justified in buying these kinds of films for their movie collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733&lt;/h3&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;RTR, which stands for read the review. A 3-star rating is a bit ambiguous; it could be an almost-good-but-not-quite film or an almost-bad-but-not-quite film. In general, I give it to films that are decent, but not exceptional. As LaSalle elaborates, “If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t transcend the genre, it will mean that someone not drawn to the genre wouldn&amp;rsquo;t like it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733 &amp;#9733&lt;/h3&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Thumbs down. Definitely bad and not worth seeing. These films usually have some redeeming qualities, but not nearly enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733&lt;/h3&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Absolutely terrible. There are few and often no merits to the film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-short-review&#34;&gt;The Short Review&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ultimate goal with the short review is to showcase the film’s merits (or lack thereof) without giving too much of the plot away. If you are looking for detailed plot summaries, go look it up on the Wikipedia or IMDB (but that&amp;rsquo;s no fun).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, people mostly skip the reviews and go straight to the ratings anyways. So for those of you who do take time out of your busy lives to read reviews, I try to make it easier by making my reviews short and simple. Many of them are 500 words or less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that my thoughts on the film are at least somewhat helpful and insightful, and that you enjoy the world of film as much as I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;http://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1480470081/bill_aqebcg.png&#39; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>