<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
  xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Kevin Li</title>
    <link>http://lilingkai.github.io/</link>
    <description>Developer, Musician, and Cineaste</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>American Beauty</title>
      <link>http://lilingkai.github.io//american-beauty-review</link>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2016-01-30T00:00:00-06:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ingeborg Holm</title>
      <link>http://lilingkai.github.io//ingeborg-holm-review</link>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ingeborg Holm” is a Swedish social drama based on a play by Nils Krok, hailing from the early days of cinema and the alien planet of silent film. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2016-01-13T00:00:00-06:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deux Jours, Une Nuit</title>
      <link>http://lilingkai.github.io//deux-jours-une-nuit-review</link>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Deux Jours, Une Nuit” (Two Days, One Night) reminds us of the people that are negatively affected by the growing wealth gap and the deteriorating middle class. The Dardenne brothers offer yet another important view into the world of the struggling, everyday Belgian worker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main character, Sandra (Marion Cotillard), is a young Belgian mother who is recovering from clinical depression. However, she returns from her sick leave to find that her boss has given her 16 coworkers a choice: receive 1000 euro bonuses or let Sandra return and keep her job. Sandra’s coworkers have already voted in favor of receiving bonuses, but the boss agrees to give her job back if Sandra can get a majority to change their mind by Monday, leaving her with just one weekend to track down her colleagues and ask them to change their votes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2016-01-12T00:00:00-06:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moonrise Kingdom</title>
      <link>http://lilingkai.github.io//moonrise-kingdom-review</link>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel and see the nostalgia of summer’s end, first love, and youth itself in “Moonrise Kingdom”. Crisp visuals and endearing performances drive this film, and while the ending might be a bit harried, I still smile at the thought of this wonderful little fictional island. It’s easy to let yourself become spellbound by the mini-universes that Wes Anderson creates in his films, and this one is no different. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2016-01-11T00:00:00-06:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Revenant</title>
      <link>http://lilingkai.github.io//the-revenant-review</link>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s not a film I particularly love, I admire “The Revenant” for its beauty, cinematography, and visceral depiction of the wild. This is a film that is meant to be seen on the big screen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2016-01-08T00:00:00-06:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carol</title>
      <link>http://lilingkai.github.io//carol-review</link>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not by any means an expert on the subject of love, but I believe “Carol” is one of the most realistic and intelligent portrayals of love that I’ve seen in film.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2016-01-05T00:00:00-06:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Hateful Eight</title>
      <link>http://lilingkai.github.io//the-hateful-eight-review</link>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quentin Tarantino’s eighth film, “The Hateful Eight”, is some sort of twisted game of Clue in the style of a Western, set ten or so years after the American Civil War. Add a stellar cast and a beautiful original score written by Ennio Morricone and we’ve got ourselves a good movie that’s entertaining as hell. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2016-01-02T00:00:00-06:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joy</title>
      <link>http://lilingkai.github.io//joy-review</link>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the film celebrates strong matriarchal characters and the power of determination, I can’t help but wish “Joy” was better. This is David O. Russell’s third film in a row featuring the talented Jennifer Lawrence, but unlike “Silver Lining’s Playbook” and “American Hustle”, “Joy” is a bumpy ride that isn’t always enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2015-12-30T00:00:00-06:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Force Awakens</title>
      <link>http://lilingkai.github.io//star-wars-the-force-awakens-review</link>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733 &amp;#9733&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most anticipated movie of the year, &amp;quot;Star Wars: The Force Awakens&amp;quot;, lives up to all the hype, and J. J. Abrams delivers the best early Christmas present I could ask for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2015-12-18T00:00:00-06:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guide to My Film Review Style</title>
      <link>http://lilingkai.github.io//guide-to-my-film-review-style</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the future, I&amp;#39;ll be posting reviews of films I watch so I can keep a film journal of sorts. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2015-12-13T00:00:00-06:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Post - Goals</title>
      <link>http://lilingkai.github.io//first-post-goals</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With fall quarter officially over, I finally found the time to get this site up and make it look decent (I hope). For my first post, I just wanted to type out what I hope this website/blog can be:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2015-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <dc:date>2016-01-30T00:00:00-06:00</dc:date>
  </channel>
</rss>