<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lilingkai.github.io</title>
   
   <link>http://lilingkai.github.io/</link>
   <description>Developer, Musician, and Cineaste</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> Kevin Li</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Joy</title>
	  <link>//joy-film-review</link>
	  <author>Kevin Li</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-12-30T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//joy-film-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3>&#9733 &#9733 &#9733</h3>

<p>With themes that celebrate strong matriarchal characters and the power of determination, I can’t help but wish “Joy” was a better film. This is David O. Russell’s third film in a row featuring the talented Jennifer Lawrence, but unlike “Silver Lining’s Playbook” and “American Hustle”, “Joy” is a bumpy ride that isn’t always enjoyable.</p>

<p>The film is loosely based on the life of Joy Mangano, inventor of the Miracle Mop and eventual founder of Home Shopping Network (HSN). The key word here is “loosely”, as much of the film is a fictional recount of Joy’s tale from rags to riches, and the name Mangano is never even mentioned. It’s best to review this film as fiction rather than a biopic.</p>

<p>Jennifer Lawrence does a fine job portraying Joy and makes us care about her and her dreams. It makes scenes with her bloodsucking leech of a family that much harder to watch because each one of them, save for her grandmother and children, seems bent on suffocating her creativity and keeping her in a subservient position.</p>

<p>The film ultimately suffers from a lack of balance, cohesion, and tonal control. I wasn’t sure whether the film was supposed to be a comedy or drama or both. The scenes that are supposed to be comedic are funny in a feel-bad kind of way since most of them are at the expense of Joy’s happiness. Scenes of despair feel cheapened when they are quickly followed by a scene of triumph. Whether or not these choices were intentional, the end result is the same: a chaotic piece of work that leaves much to be desired.</p>

<hr>

<p>Director: David O. Russell</p>

<p>Starring: Jennifer Lawrence, Robert De Niro, Bradley Cooper</p>

<p>PG-13, 124 min</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Force Awakens</title>
	  <link>//star-wars-the-force-awakens</link>
	  <author>Kevin Li</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-12-18T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//star-wars-the-force-awakens</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3>&#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733</h3>

<p>The most anticipated movie of the year, &quot;Star Wars: The Force Awakens&quot;, lives up to all the hype, and J. J. Abrams delivers the best early Christmas present I could ask for.</p>

<p>The seventh installment of the famed franchise arrives three years after George Lucas sold Lucasfilm to Disney. The sale allowed Disney to take control of the story, and they decided to depart from Lucas&#39; original outline. Sounds scary I know, but the fandom can rest assured as the Force is apparently strong with Disney, and they&#39;ve created a brilliant space opera. </p>

<p>Much like the original trilogy, “The Force Awakens” is a classic good versus bad story, but this time it’s fueled with exciting new characters, Rey (Daisy Ridley), Finn (John Boyega), and Poe (Oscar Isaac) alongside the iconic originals, Han Solo (Harrison Ford), Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher), and Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill). The film takes place three decades after the events of “Return of the Jedi” and the familiar slanted word scroll fills us in with the details of the past thirty years. In short: Luke Skywalker has vanished, and in his absence, the ashes of the old Empire have given birth to The First Order, a new threat to all peaceful systems and planets. It’s a race to see who can find Luke faster; the bad guys need to destroy the last Jedi knight, and the good guys need him to lead their side to victory.</p>

<p>Abrams tells the story with masterful pacing and balance. From action sequences to character development or sentimental drama to comic relief, the film never misses a beat. The plot is always driving forward, yet it seems to take its time traveling through the magnificent world that has been built, complete with its own eclectic mix of alien species and droids.</p>

<p>The seamless integration of new and old characters is a true testament to the success of the film. The new characters are never overshadowed by the old, and Ridley and Boyega have great chemistry with Ford, who acts as a sort of father figure while retaining the grumpy and irreverant attitude of Han Solo that fans have come to know and love. It’s safe to say that many viewers will walk out of the theater finding that while Luke, Han, and Leia still hold a special place in their hearts, they&#39;ve also made room for the young Rey and Finn (and the adorable droid, BB-8). </p>

<p>Of course, the film isn’t perfect, but was perfection ever a feasibility? It certainly isn&#39;t possible to please everybody. Some fans might be disappointed with the supposed power of the Dark Side, or the fact that the plot errs on the safe side. But for every &quot;wrong&quot;, there are ten more things that Abrams gets right.  </p>

<p>To discuss the film in further detail here would be a crime; just go and experience what the whole world is buzzing about for yourself.</p>

<p>“Episode VIII” is scheduled for release on May 26, 2017. It’s going to be a long seventeen months.</p>

<hr>

<p>Director: J.J. Abrams</p>

<p>Starring: Daisy Ridley, John Boyega, Oscar Isaac, Adam Driver, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Mark Hamill</p>

<p>PG-13, 135 min</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Guide to My Film Review Style</title>
	  <link>//guide-to-my-film-review-style</link>
	  <author>Kevin Li</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-12-13T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//guide-to-my-film-review-style</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>In the future, I&#39;ll be posting reviews of films I watch so I can keep a film journal of sorts. </p>

<p>The basic format will consist of 2-3 parts:</p>

<ul>
<li>My rating on a 5 star scale</li>
<li>A short review</li>
<li>An extended review</li>
</ul>

<p>Every film I review will have a rating and a short review. Some reviews might also include an extended version. I&#39;ve briefly explained what all this means below:</p>

<h4>The 5 Star Rating System</h4>

<p>The system is quite similar to the “Little Man System”, which was conceived by Mick LaSalle, film critic for the San Francisco Chronicle. </p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>5 &quot;Gold&quot;</strong>: The great films. It is usually reserved for films I absolutely loved and would happily watch again and again.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>4 &quot;Thumbs-Up&quot;</strong>: Definitely good, very enjoyable, and not quite great. People are justified in buying these kinds of films for their movie collection.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>3 &quot;RTR&quot;</strong>: Which stands for read the review. Nothing screams &quot;GRAY AREA&quot; more than the middle of the spectrum. A 3-star rating is a bit ambiguous; it could be an almost-good-but-not-quite film or an almost-bad-but-not-quite film. In general, I give it to films that are decent, but not exceptional. As LaSalle elaborates, “If it doesn&#39;t transcend the genre, it will mean that someone not drawn to the genre wouldn&#39;t like it.”</p></li>
<li><p><strong>2 &quot;Thumbs-Down&quot;</strong>: Definitely bad and not worth seeing. These films usually have some redeeming features, but not nearly enough.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>1 &quot;:(&quot;</strong>: Absolutely terrible. There are few and often no merits to the film.</p></li>
</ul>

<h4>The Short Review</h4>

<p>My ultimate goal with the short review is to showcase the film’s merits (or lack thereof) without giving too much of the plot away. If you are looking for detailed plot summaries, go look it up on the Internet.</p>

<p>These days, people mostly skip the reviews and go straight to the ratings anyways. So for those of you who do take time out of your busy lives to read reviews, I try to make it easier by making my reviews short and simple. Many of them sit around 200 words or less. </p>

<h4>The Extended Review</h4>

<p>Sometimes, I will write an extended review, which goes much more in depth than the short review. I will assume the reader has seen the movies, so don&#39;t come crying to me about spoilers.</p>

<p>I hope that my thoughts on the film are at least somewhat helpful and insightful, and that you enjoy the world of film as much as I do. </p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
