<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>lilingkai.github.io</title>
   
   <link>http://lilingkai.github.io/</link>
   <description>Developer, Musician, & Film Enthusiast</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> Kevin Li</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Blue Jasmine</title>
	  <link>//blue-jasmine-review</link>
	  <author>Kevin Li</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//blue-jasmine-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3>&#9733 &#9733 &#9733</h3>

<p>It’s Cate Blanchett’s Oscar-winning performance that makes “Blue Jasmine” worth watching. Sadly, it’s not enough to make this Woody Allen film rise out of the woodwork.</p>

<p>Blanchett plays Jasmine, a New York socialite trying to get herself back on her feet in San Francisco. We get hints about her past in the form of flashbacks, which are interspersed throughout the film; her ex-husband was a very rich businessman, but something went wrong, and now she must move in with her sister and see if she can rebuild her life. Not only is she broke, but she also suffers from anxiety breakdowns and speaks to herself as if she is reliving the days when she was still living the high life in New York. Jasmine’s a deplorable, narcissistic character, and throughout the film you feel pity, frustration, and annoyance as you watch this broken trophy wife attempt to survive. </p>

<p>We can’t forget about the rest of the cast surrounding Blanchett, who all do stellar work as well. Unfortunately, most of their characters are not very well written and don’t feel like real people. Would a single mother with two children who bags groceries really be able to afford such a spacious apartment in San Francisco? But I digress. </p>

<p>If I were forced to pinpoint what the film’s main focus was, I would say women and mental illness, yet it doesn’t say anything profound or groundbreaking.</p>

<p>Still, the film will entertain you, even if at the end you might be thinking, “So what?”</p>

<hr>

<p>Director: Woody Allen</p>

<p>Starring: Cate Blanchett, Sally Hawkin, Alec Baldwin</p>

<p>PG-13, 98 min</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Princess Mononoke</title>
	  <link>//mononoke-hime-review</link>
	  <author>Kevin Li</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-31T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//mononoke-hime-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3>&#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733</h3>

<p>Hayao Miyazaki proves he is a true master of storytelling in this battle between nature and humans, love and hate, war and peace, life and death. The story is set during medieval Japan, right at the coming of the Iron Age, where humans either live in peace with nature or die trying to tame it.</p>

<p>In the first moments of the movie, we meet Ashitaka, the prince of a small, peaceful village in the East. Suddenly, the village is under attack by a cursed boar-god with skin made of writhing grey worms. Ashitaka successfully defeats this demon, but in the process, his arm was infected by the same curse that afflicted the boar-god. In order to find a way to lift the curse, he sets off on a journey to the West, where he finds himself in the middle of a war between the forest gods, an iron-working colony, and the samurai enclave nearby. </p>

<p>Miyazaki doesn&#39;t make morality come so easily as there is no clear good vs. evil here; most human characters have two sides to them, and the forest gods are drawn not like &quot;Bambi&quot; animals but like fierce creatures who can and will kill if necessary. </p>

<p>The level of detail in the animation is astounding, and the complexity of the film is unrivaled by other animated films and most live-actions as well. The hand-drawn frames certainly bring an atmospheric quality to the film, and while it might not look as slick as some of the computer-assisted films like “Spirited Away”, the film is still beautiful to watch. This is all supplemented by Joe Hisaishi’s exquisite film score. </p>

<p>It&#39;s a fantastical story of epic proportions. I have probably seen this movie at least a dozen times now, and it never fails to impress me time and time again. Bravo Miyazaki, bravo.</p>

<hr>

<p>Director: Hayao Miyazaki</p>

<p>PG-13, 134 min.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Cloud Atlas</title>
	  <link>//cloud-atlas-review</link>
	  <author>Kevin Li</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-31T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//cloud-atlas-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3>&#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733</h3>

<p>A daring work of art showcasing what the magic of cinema has to offer! &quot;Cloud Atlas&quot; manages to be a science-fiction, historical drama, action, mystery, thriller, romance, comedy, and much more. There are six different story lines, spanning from the 1800’s to the 2300’s or so, all told together beyond the bounds of narrative continuity. The same actors are used in multiple story lines, disguised in makeup and costumed so cleverly that sometimes they are unrecognizable.</p>

<p>The film is almost 3 hours, yet I was never bored. To be honest, I wouldn&#39;t have minded if it were longer just to flesh out some of the story lines. I normally would attempt to give a short description of the plot, but I think I would just lose you all the same in trying to describe the six different timelines and all their characters. Sometimes, it is better to just sit back and watch. </p>

<p>Yet, such a complex film warrants discussion as to what it all means. I can throw out a few ideas: connection, separation, time, friendship, love, life. But to pinpoint the film to a single ideology is perhaps as fruitless as trying to catch the clouds. I like to think of “Cloud Atlas” as a film to be enjoyed much like how one sits back and watches the clouds naturally transform to different shapes, taking our imaginations on a grand adventure.</p>

<hr>

<p>Director: Tom Tykwer, Andy and Lana Wachowski</p>

<p>Starring: Tom Hanks, Halle Berry, Jim Broadbent, Hugo Weaving, Jim Sturgess, Doona Bae, Bem Wjosjaw, Keith David, James D&#39;Arcy, Xun Zhou, David Gyasi, Susan Sarandon, Hugh Grant </p>

<p>R, 172 min.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Boyhood</title>
	  <link>//boyhood-review</link>
	  <author>Kevin Li</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-31T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//boyhood-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3>&#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733</h3>

<p>What a remarkable coming-of-age story and a beautifully human film. This twelve-year project where we witness a boy grow from ages 6 to 18 in the span of 165 min is simply captivating. I was deeply moved by the film and often found myself reminiscing on what my own boyhood was like. </p>

<p>The drama presented on screen is not blown up to Hollywood scale, but stays true to everyday life. There isn’t really a narrative; we’re just watching people trying to figure out things as they go. To see the developing maturity and transformations of the whole cast as they wrestle with the struggles of life and growing older is fascinating and greatly rewarding.  </p>

<p>Yes, it’s not a perfect film. I found most conversation scenes to be edited in a painfully distracting back-and-forth manner, and the child acting may seem a bit too childish at times. But I think to pick away at the flaws of the film is missing the point. Life is far from perfect; the ride is often bumpy and we seem to run into a lot of dead ends. “What’s the point? I sure as shit don’t know” says the father, “We’re all just winging it.” You don’t have to be a boy to relate to that.</p>

<hr>

<p>Director: Richard Linklater</p>

<p>Starring: Ellar Coltrane, Patricia Arquette, Ethan Hawke</p>

<p>R, 165 min</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>American Beauty</title>
	  <link>//american-beauty-review</link>
	  <author>Kevin Li</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-30T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//american-beauty-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3>&#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733</h3>

<p>I have probably seen this film six or seven times at this point, and it remains one of my favorite movies of all time.</p>

<p>&quot;American Beauty” is the story of Lester Burnham (Kevin Spacey), a middle-aged father who awakens from his mid-life slump thanks to his infatuation with his daughter’s best friend.</p>

<p>Some of you are already turned off by the description and ready to skip this film; I urge you to reconsider. While the premise of the film is based on a Lolita relationship, the film is more focused on what it has to say about youth, happiness, power, beauty, and life itself.</p>

<p>The cinematography and the performances by the cast, coupled with Thomas Newman&#39;s beautiful score, are reason enough to see this film. Kevin Spacey&#39;s performance is a marvel and a treat to watch; he plays a character where we see all of his worst qualities, and yet we still love him and root for him all the same. </p>

<p>It&#39;s a complex and different kind of film than you are probably used to, one where there are no truly good or bad characters and where there are moments so funny that it hurts to keep laughing and others that are so tragic that we are surprised to find ourselves so deeply moved. Almost everyone can relate to the problems of growing old, finding love and happiness, and losing relevancy in their lives, and that&#39;s what makes “American Beauty” such a powerful and great film.</p>

<hr>

<p>Director: Sam Mendes</p>

<p>Starring: Kevin Spacey, Annette Bening</p>

<p>R, 122 min</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Ingeborg Holm</title>
	  <link>//ingeborg-holm-review</link>
	  <author>Kevin Li</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-13T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//ingeborg-holm-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3>&#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733</h3>

<p>“Ingeborg Holm” is a Swedish social drama based on a play by Nils Krok, hailing from the early days of cinema and the alien planet of silent film. </p>

<p>“But why on earth would you want to watch old, silent, black and white movies? They’re so boring!” Well, I didn’t really have a choice in this case since I’m currently taking History of Film I and I’m responsible for knowing the film. And yes, I understand that most twenty-first century movies are more appealing and more exciting to our modern eyes. But even so, I’m glad to have seen this film, and I hope that I can help some of you better understand and appreciate the merits of silent film.</p>

<p>This is the story of Ingeborg Holm (Hilda Borgstöm), a young Swedish woman who is happily married and a mother to three children. Her husband gets a loan to open their new shop, but things take a grim turn when he suddenly falls ill. Even though I suspect almost none of you will actually watch the film, I cannot spoil the rest of the plot in good conscience. The film’s Wikipedia page provides a conclusive summary if you wish to know the details. All that you need to know is that the film is tragic, and just when you think things couldn’t be any worse… well you’re wrong.</p>

<p>The world of silent black and white film might as well be a different planet to modern audiences; it’s like watching animated grey ghosts who seem so distant from us that it can be hard to relate to characters. But with “Ingeborg Holm”, I was surprised at the clarity of the narrative, told only with visual compositions and a little help from a few title cards. It also helps that Hilda Borgstöm gives an engaging performance as the main lead; I was able to see and feel the emotional pain that she was constantly experiencing. The pacing and directing is all good; with Sjöström’s restraint, the film surprisingly doesn’t descend into some weepy melodrama. </p>

<p>Even though the movie is over a hundred years old, the picture quality of the 16mm film held up surprisingly well, although there were a few spots where the nitrate deterioration is more than noticeable. </p>

<p>It’s definitely not a feel-good kind of movie, but I would recommend it for the fans of the silent genre and hardcore movie watchers looking to gain an encyclopedic knowledge of all things film. </p>

<hr>

<p>Director: Victor Sjöström</p>

<p>Starring: Hilda Borgström, Aron Lindgren</p>

<p>1913 (Sweden), 96 min</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Deux Jours, Une Nuit</title>
	  <link>//deux-jours-une-nuit-review</link>
	  <author>Kevin Li</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-12T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//deux-jours-une-nuit-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3>&#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733</h3>

<p>“Deux Jours, Une Nuit” (Two Days, One Night) reminds us of the people that are negatively affected by the growing wealth gap and the deteriorating middle class. The Dardenne brothers offer yet another important view into the world of the struggling, everyday Belgian worker.</p>

<p>The main character, Sandra (Marion Cotillard), is a young Belgian mother who is recovering from clinical depression. However, she returns from her sick leave to find that her boss has given her 16 coworkers a choice: receive 1000 euro bonuses or let Sandra return and keep her job. Sandra’s coworkers have already voted in favor of receiving bonuses, but the boss agrees to give her job back if Sandra can get a majority to change their mind by Monday, leaving her with just one weekend to track down her colleagues and ask them to change their votes.</p>

<p>It’s a troubling and unfair predicament for everyone. While no one really wants Sandra to lose her job, the 1000 euros could really come in handy for some of these people. What would you say or do?</p>

<p>Unfortunately, the premise of the film naturally lends itself to repetition. Even though every coworker’s circumstances are different, we get the idea by the sixth or seventh coworker: they will either change their vote, or simply say no (sometimes not so politely). The formula works, but eventually all good things succumb to the law of diminishing returns.</p>

<p>But it&#39;s the simplicity and the honesty of the social drama that makes “Deux Jours, Une Nuit” a good film. It also helps that nearly every shot includes Cotillard, whose performance deservedly warranted an Oscar nomination. Her weary eyes, heavy walk, and defeatist emotions accurately portray the life of depression. We truly get the feeling that she’s just fighting to stay afloat. </p>

<p>Sometimes, it’s not the story of triumphant success that interests us, but the story of just surviving; something that I’m sure we can all relate to.</p>

<hr>

<p>Directors: Jean-Pierre Dardenne, Luc Dardenne</p>

<p>Starring: Marion Cotillard, Fabrizio Rongione</p>

<p>2014 (Belgium), PG-13, 95 min</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Moonrise Kingdom</title>
	  <link>//moonrise-kingdom-review</link>
	  <author>Kevin Li</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-11T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//moonrise-kingdom-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3>&#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733</h3>

<p>I feel and see the nostalgia of summer’s end, first love, and youth itself in “Moonrise Kingdom”. Crisp visuals and endearing performances drive this film, and while the ending might be a bit harried, I still smile at the thought of this wonderful little fictional island. It’s easy to let yourself become spellbound by the mini-universes that Wes Anderson creates in his films, and this one is no different. </p>

<p>The film is set during the summer of 1965 on a New England island where our hero, Sam (Jared Gilman), attends Khaki Scout Camp, and our heroine, Suzy (Kara Hayward), lives with family. Sam and Suzy met last summer and have been plotting their escape from their current living situations since then. The island isn’t very big, but they’re confident they can find their own hideout.</p>

<p>Their disappearance sparks a search-and-rescue mission from the adult world, led by the island&#39;s only police officer (Bruce Willis), the scoutmaster (Edward Norton), and Suzy’s parents, (Bill Murray and Frances McDormand). Even though the world of adults and the world of children were almost always shown separately, I had the feeling that they were not so different from each other in that both were driven by desires and emotion, and that they were all people just trying to figure out life for themselves.</p>

<p>Or perhaps I’m getting ahead of myself. After all, the film has its own on-screen narrator, plays out and looks like a children’s storybook, and has a character who is only referred to as Social Services (Tilda Swinton). Life as it is portrayed in the film isn’t quite like ours, but you might be surprised to find a little bit of yourself in “Moonrise Kingdom”.</p>

<hr>

<p>Director: Wes Anderson</p>

<p>Starring: Jared Gilman, Kara Hayward, Bruce Willis, Edward Norton, Bill Murray, Frances McDormand, Tilda Swinton</p>

<p>2012, PG-13, 96 min</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Revenant</title>
	  <link>//the-revenant-review</link>
	  <author>Kevin Li</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-08T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//the-revenant-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3>&#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733</h3>

<p>While it’s not a film I particularly love, I admire “The Revenant” for its beauty, cinematography, and visceral depiction of the wild. This is a film that is meant to be seen on the big screen.</p>

<p>“The Revenant” is the survival story of Hugh Glass (Leonardo DiCaprio), a fur trapper who was betrayed by John Fitzgerald (Tom Hardy) and left by his companions for dead after being mauled by a bear. It’s a mesmerizing experience, and Alejandro Iñárritu captures the grizzly beauty of the unforgiving mountains and the cold winter.</p>

<p>Leonardo DiCaprio and Tom Hardy both give great performances, but it’s hard to compare the two. DiCaprio doesn’t have many lines throughout the film, so all of the acting comes from physical action and from the eyes. To portray a man who experiences pain and hardship every step of the journey is certainly not easy, and it’s a haunting performance that makes viewers meditate on the limits of the human body and our drive to survive. Hardy’s character is a bit more nuanced as he has the most dialogue. His American accent is very convincing but sometimes sounds like he has five marbles in his mouth. Not that it really matters anyway, most of the dialogue in the film is not very interesting or cliché.</p>

<p>But you don&#39;t go see &quot;The Revenant&quot; for its interesting dialogue (go see &quot;The Hateful Eight&quot; if you want dialogue); most of the appeal in the film comes from the visuals. However, the luscious pictures start to lose its effect on you as time drags. While the first third of the film will wow most viewers, others might start to feel the length during the middle, and the last third disappoints as it had strange pacing issues and the potential for being interesting.  </p>

<p>The film also doesn’t establish any substantial emotional connection with the characters. By the end of the film, I couldn’t care less which man would emerge on top. But the film certainly accomplishes its quest to overwhelm our senses with scenes of grit and blood in a wild, beautiful, and dangerous place where humans don’t belong.</p>

<hr>

<p>Director: Alejandro González Iñárritu</p>

<p>Starring: Leonardo DiCaprio, Tom Hardy</p>

<p>2015, R, 156 min</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Carol</title>
	  <link>//carol-review</link>
	  <author>Kevin Li</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-05T00:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//carol-review</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3>&#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733 &#9733</h3>

<p>I am not by any means an expert on the subject of love, but I believe “Carol” is one of the most realistic and intelligent portrayals of love that I’ve seen in film.</p>

<p>Based on Patricia Highsmith’s novel, “The Price of Salt”, “Carol” is a beautiful love story set in 1950’s New York that features two main characters. The first one we meet is Therese (Rooney Mara), a young, doll-like woman in her 20’s who works in the doll-section of the toy store, but aspires to be a photographer. The other is Carol (Cate Blanchett), a socialite, wife, and mother, who enters the toy store looking to buy a doll for her daughter. It’s in this simple store that the two women first meet and begin their relationship. </p>

<p>The film does a lot more showing than telling, something that’s all too rare in today’s cinema. Todd Haynes’ restraint creates a romance that doesn’t descend into the land of the hormonal, and it feels a bit more like we’re seeing real people trying to figure out what the other person is thinking and at what level is their relationship.</p>

<p>Of course, that wouldn’t have been possible had it not been for Cate Blanchett and Rooney Mara’s great performances. It&#39;s the subtle gestures in their acting that allow us to see how they fall in love. Blanchett’s poise and voice are bewitching, and Mara draws us in with her a mysterious Hepburn-like character, a bit of an alien “flung out of space” as Carol describes her. </p>

<p>This is all shot with careful detail to depict 1950’s America. The sets and costumes with their record players, cars, furniture, clothing, hair, and cigarettes are immaculately presented. Much of the film is shot through windows, as if we are looking through the glass, wondering what we will discover there. You’ll be pleased to find something beautiful and deeply human looking back at you.</p>

<hr>

<p>Director: Todd Haynes</p>

<p>Starring: Cate Blanchett, Rooney Mara</p>

<p>2015, R, 118 min</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
