<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Film Review on Kevin Li</title>
    <link>https://lilingkai.github.io/tags/film-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Film Review on Kevin Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lilingkai.github.io/tags/film-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Revenant</title>
      <link>https://lilingkai.github.io/2016/01/the-revenant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lilingkai.github.io/2016/01/the-revenant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While it’s not a film I particularly love, I admire “The Revenant” for its beauty, cinematography, and visceral depiction of the wild. This is a film that is meant to be seen on the big screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Revenant” is the survival story of Hugh Glass (Leonardo DiCaprio), a fur trapper who was betrayed by John Fitzgerald (Tom Hardy) and left by his companions for dead after being mauled by a bear. It’s a mesmerizing experience, and Alejandro Iñárritu captures the grizzly beauty of the unforgiving mountains and the cold winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leonardo DiCaprio and Tom Hardy both give great performances, but it’s hard to compare the two. DiCaprio doesn’t have many lines throughout the film, so all of the acting comes from physical action and from the eyes. To portray a man who experiences pain and hardship every step of the journey is certainly not easy, and it’s a haunting performance that makes viewers meditate on the limits of the human body and our drive to survive. Hardy’s character is a bit more nuanced as he has the most dialogue. His American accent is very convincing but sometimes sounds like he has five marbles in his mouth. Not that it really matters anyway, most of the dialogue in the film is not very interesting or cliché.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you don&amp;rsquo;t go see &amp;ldquo;The Revenant&amp;rdquo; for its interesting dialogue (go see &amp;ldquo;The Hateful Eight&amp;rdquo; if you want dialogue); most of the appeal in the film comes from the visuals. However, the luscious pictures start to lose its effect on you as time drags. While the first third of the film will wow most viewers, others might start to feel the length during the middle, and the last third disappoints as it had strange pacing issues and the potential for being interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film also doesn’t establish any substantial emotional connection with the characters. By the end of the film, I couldn’t care less which man would emerge on top. But the film certainly accomplishes its quest to overwhelm our senses with scenes of grit and blood in a wild, beautiful, and dangerous place where humans don’t belong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: Alejandro González Iñárritu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starring: Leonardo DiCaprio, Tom Hardy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015, R, 156 min&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carol</title>
      <link>https://lilingkai.github.io/2016/01/carol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lilingkai.github.io/2016/01/carol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am not by any means an expert on the subject of love, but I believe “Carol” is one of the most realistic and intelligent portrayals of love that I’ve seen in film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on Patricia Highsmith’s novel, “The Price of Salt”, “Carol” is a beautiful love story set in 1950’s New York that features two main characters. The first one we meet is Therese (Rooney Mara), a young, doll-like woman in her 20’s who works in the doll-section of the toy store, but aspires to be a photographer. The other is Carol (Cate Blanchett), a socialite, wife, and mother, who enters the toy store looking to buy a doll for her daughter. It’s in this simple store that the two women first meet and begin their relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film does a lot more showing than telling, something that’s all too rare in today’s cinema. Todd Haynes’ restraint creates a romance that doesn’t descend into the land of the hormonal, and it feels a bit more like we’re seeing real people trying to figure out what the other person is thinking and at what level is their relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, that wouldn’t have been possible had it not been for Cate Blanchett and Rooney Mara’s great performances. It&amp;rsquo;s the subtle gestures in their acting that allow us to see how they fall in love. Blanchett’s poise and voice are bewitching, and Mara draws us in with her a mysterious Hepburn-like character, a bit of an alien “flung out of space” as Carol describes her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all shot with careful detail to depict 1950’s America. The sets and costumes with their record players, cars, furniture, clothing, hair, and cigarettes are immaculately presented. Much of the film is shot through windows, as if we are looking through the glass, wondering what we will discover there. You’ll be pleased to find something beautiful and deeply human looking back at you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: Todd Haynes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starring: Cate Blanchett, Rooney Mara&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015, R, 118 min&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hateful Eight</title>
      <link>https://lilingkai.github.io/2016/01/the-hateful-eight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lilingkai.github.io/2016/01/the-hateful-eight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quentin Tarantino’s eighth film, “The Hateful Eight”, is some sort of twisted game of Clue in the style of a Western, set ten or so years after the American Civil War.  Add a stellar cast and a beautiful original score written by Ennio Morricone and we’ve got ourselves a good movie that’s entertaining as hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This film is very different from other Tarantino films, which featured clear protagonists; the characters in “The Hateful Eight” are more complex and certainly more hateful. We’re not sure who to root for since all of them are untrustworthy, making it all the more exciting to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the film does lack some depth. While “Inglorious” and “Django” were set in significant historical events that gave them a sense of something greater than themselves, “The Hateful Eight” seems to be more of a gruesome celebration of the story itself. Still, it’s an impressive story, even if it might not mean anything in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kurt Russell plays a bounty hunter who is transporting the murderer Daisy (Jennifer Jason Leigh) to her hanging. Along the road, he picks up Major Marquis Warren (Samuel L. Jackson), another bounty hunter, and the new sheriff of the town, played by Walton Goggins. When they find shelter at a cabin, we’re introduced to another set of characters: a mysterious cowboy (Michael Madsen), an Englishman (Tim Roth), the Mexican horse caretaker (Demián Bichir), and the Confederate general (Bruce Dern). As the blizzard descends upon them, the cast is officially trapped inside, and the rest of the plot unfolds in the cozy cabin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pacing of this three hour grandiose film could be described with the metaphor of the boiling frog. For those of you who are unfamiliar, if you place a frog in a pot of cold water and turn the stove on low heat, the water will gradually heat up, and before long, the frog will unresistingly allow itself to be boiled to death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the audience is the frog, then the first chapter of the film is the cold water, aptly set in the wintery Wyoming mountainside. The film takes its sweet time assembling its hateful crew together, and tension grows as the water is starting to heat up.  With all the juicy, Tarantino-style dialogue and excellent performances from Jackson, Goggins, and Leigh (to name a few of the standout performances), you don’t even realize two hours has already passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The water is starting to reach the boiling point as we enter the final chapters of the film, which takes a turn for the grotesquely violent side. If you thought “Inglorious” or “Django” was hard to watch, “The Hateful Eight” is much worse. There are moments so gruesome that your stomach might do a flip or two, and others that are so ridiculous that it’s hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Hateful Eight” is perhaps the funniest and definitely the bloodiest Tarantino film to date, and I look forward to seeing what the genius director/writer decides to make next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: Quentin Tarantino&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starring: Samuel L. Jackson, Kurt Russell, Jennifer Jason Leigh, Walton Goggins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015, R, 187 min&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy</title>
      <link>https://lilingkai.github.io/2015/12/joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lilingkai.github.io/2015/12/joy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the film celebrates strong matriarchal characters and the power of determination, I can’t help but wish “Joy” was better.This is David O. Russell’s third film in a row featuring the talented Jennifer Lawrence, but unlike “Silver Lining’s Playbook” and “American Hustle”, “Joy” is a bumpy ride that isn’t always enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film is loosely based on the life of Joy Mangano, inventor of the Miracle Mop and eventual founder of Home Shopping Network (HSN). The key word here is “loosely”, as much of the film is a fictional recount of Joy’s tale from rags to riches, and the name Mangano is never even mentioned. It’s best to review this film as fiction rather than a biopic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jennifer Lawrence does a fine job portraying Joy and makes us care about her and her dreams. It makes scenes with her bloodsucking leech of a family that much harder to watch because each one of them, save for her grandmother and children, seems bent on suffocating her creativity and keeping her in a subservient position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film ultimately suffers from a lack of balance, cohesion, and tonal control. I wasn’t sure whether the film was supposed to be a comedy or drama or both. The scenes that are supposed to be comedic are funny in a feel-bad kind of way since most of them are at the expense of Joy’s happiness. Scenes of despair feel cheapened when they are quickly followed by a scene of triumph. Whether or not these choices were intentional, the end result is the same: a chaotic work that leaves much to be desired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: David O. Russell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starring: Jennifer Lawrence, Robert De Niro, Bradley Cooper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015, PG-13, 124 min&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Force Awakens</title>
      <link>https://lilingkai.github.io/2015/12/the-force-awakens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lilingkai.github.io/2015/12/the-force-awakens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most anticipated movie of the year, &amp;ldquo;Star Wars: The Force Awakens&amp;rdquo;, lives up to all the hype, and J. J. Abrams delivers the best early Christmas present I could ask for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seventh installment of the famed franchise arrives three years after George Lucas sold Lucasfilm to Disney. The sale allowed Disney to take control of the story, and they decided to depart from Lucas&amp;rsquo; original outline. Sounds scary I know, but the fandom can rest assured as the Force is apparently strong with Disney, and they&amp;rsquo;ve created a brilliant space opera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like the original trilogy, “The Force Awakens” is a classic good versus bad story, but this time it’s fueled with exciting new characters, Rey (Daisy Ridley), Finn (John Boyega), and Poe (Oscar Isaac) alongside the iconic originals, Han Solo (Harrison Ford), Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher), and Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill). The film takes place three decades after the events of “Return of the Jedi” and the familiar slanted word scroll fills us in with the details of the past thirty years. In short: Luke Skywalker has vanished, and in his absence, the ashes of the old Empire have given birth to The First Order, a new threat to all peaceful systems and planets. It’s a race to see who can find Luke faster; the bad guys need to destroy the last Jedi knight, and the good guys need him to lead their side to victory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abrams tells the story with masterful pacing and balance. From action sequences to character development or sentimental drama to comic relief, the film never misses a beat. The plot is always driving forward, yet it seems to take its time traveling through the magnificent world that has been built, complete with its own eclectic mix of alien species and droids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seamless integration of new and old characters is a true testament to the success of the film. The new characters are never overshadowed by the old, and Ridley and Boyega have great chemistry with Ford, who acts as a sort of father figure while retaining the grumpy and irreverent attitude of Han Solo that fans have come to know and love. It’s safe to say that many viewers will walk out of the theater finding that while Luke, Han, and Leia still hold a special place in their hearts, they&amp;rsquo;ve also made room for the young Rey and Finn (and the adorable droid, BB-8).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the film isn’t perfect, but was perfection ever a feasibility? It certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t possible to please everybody. Some fans might be disappointed with the supposed power of the Dark Side, or the fact that the plot errs on the safe side. But for every &amp;ldquo;wrong&amp;rdquo;, there are ten more things that Abrams gets right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To discuss the film in further detail here would be a crime; just go and experience what the whole world is buzzing about for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: J.J. Abrams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starring: Daisy Ridley, John Boyega, Oscar Isaac, Adam Driver, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Mark Hamill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015, PG-13, 135 min&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>