<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pg 13 on Kevin Li</title>
    <link>http://kevinwli.com/tags/pg-13/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pg 13 on Kevin Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://kevinwli.com/tags/pg-13/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Wonder Woman</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2017-06-06-wonder-woman-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2017-06-06-wonder-woman-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me just say that while many genres have my sympathy, the superhero genre is usually not one of them. With the exception of Nolan&amp;rsquo;s Batman films, I find many superhero movies to be rather lukewarm with their predictable outcomes and action scenes for the sake of action. However, Wonder Woman blew away all of my expectations and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;https://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1496803348/721360_v4mirg.jpg&#39; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film begins on Themyscira, a paradise island inhabited by the Amazons that was hidden away by Zeus from the god of war, Ares. One day, a soldier crash lands his plane on the island, quickly followed by German ships. The soldier is Steve Trevor (Chris Pine), and it&amp;rsquo;s World War I. Trevor has to get back to Allied terrority to deliver intel that could help stop the war, and Diana (Gal Gadot) joins him, which thrusts her into the world of men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps one of the most entertaining parts of the film is watching the naive Diana (who knows nothing of the modern world), learning about things like revolving doors, ice cream, or early 20th century fashion. But at the same time, her eyes are also opened to the atrocities of war and destruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It almost seems as if Gadot was born for this role as she embodies the strength and heart of Wonder Woman so well. She also has good chemistry with Pine, and their characters work well together on screen, making for some hilarious exchanges. It&amp;rsquo;s also fun to see Steve always trying to catch up to Diana covering up for her naive decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the critiques that I usually have with superhero films are absent in Wonder Woman. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel that the fight scenes were over-gratuitous or that the ending was predictable. Some people might find the last act a bit cheesy, but I think it works for the film and to be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for that stuff anyway. One thing that I felt was missing was more development for the supporting characters. Steve&amp;rsquo;s companions don&amp;rsquo;t have a lasting impact on me, and there are times when some of the villains seem almost comically/one-dimensionally evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But overall, I think the thing that sets Wonder Woman apart from the rest of the superhero fodder is the fact that there is something kinder and more compassionate at its core. Perhaps it comes simply from the values that Wonder Woman stands for. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s the difference in having a female hero rather than a male one. Perhaps its both and more. All in all, the film is beautifully and intelligently made, and that in itself makes me excited to see it again. Jenkins shows the boys how its done, and I look forward to what she has to bring to Wonder Woman 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: Patty Jenkins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starring: Gal Gadot, Chris Pine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2017, PG-13, 141 min&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#10084;&amp;#xFE0E; : I think I&#39;m in love with Gal Gadot. &lt;br&gt; I&#39;m (half) joking but in all seriousness, this woman is almost too beautiful, in an almost spell-bounding kind of way that captures the attention of men and woman alike. Patty Jenkins knows what she&#39;s doing when she&#39;s giving us all those gratuitous close-up face shots of Gal. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2015-12-30-joy-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2015-12-30-joy-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the film celebrates strong matriarchal characters and the power of determination, I can’t help but wish “Joy” was better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;https://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/s--U4diYn5P--/c_scale,q_jpegmini:1,w_1600/v1480470084/Joy_g8smuu.jpg&#39; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is David O. Russell’s third film in a row featuring the talented Jennifer Lawrence, but unlike “Silver Lining’s Playbook” and “American Hustle”, “Joy” is a bumpy ride that isn’t always enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film is loosely based on the life of Joy Mangano, inventor of the Miracle Mop and eventual founder of Home Shopping Network (HSN). The key word here is “loosely”, as much of the film is a fictional recount of Joy’s tale from rags to riches, and the name Mangano is never even mentioned. It’s best to review this film as fiction rather than a biopic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jennifer Lawrence does a fine job portraying Joy and makes us care about her and her dreams. It makes scenes with her bloodsucking leech of a family that much harder to watch because each one of them, save for her grandmother and children, seems bent on suffocating her creativity and keeping her in a subservient position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film ultimately suffers from a lack of balance, cohesion, and tonal control. I wasn’t sure whether the film was supposed to be a comedy or drama or both. The scenes that are supposed to be comedic are funny in a feel-bad kind of way since most of them are at the expense of Joy’s happiness. Scenes of despair feel cheapened when they are quickly followed by a scene of triumph. Whether or not these choices were intentional, the end result is the same: a chaotic work that leaves much to be desired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: David O. Russell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starring: Jennifer Lawrence, Robert De Niro, Bradley Cooper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015, PG-13, 124 min&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Force Awakens</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2015-12-18-star-wars-the-force-awakens-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2015-12-18-star-wars-the-force-awakens-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most anticipated movie of the year, &amp;ldquo;Star Wars: The Force Awakens&amp;rdquo;, lives up to all the hype, and J. J. Abrams delivers the best early Christmas present I could ask for.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;https://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/v1480470079/starwars_sbmgqh.jpg&#39; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seventh installment of the famed franchise arrives three years after George Lucas sold Lucasfilm to Disney. The sale allowed Disney to take control of the story, and they decided to depart from Lucas&amp;rsquo; original outline. Sounds scary I know, but the fandom can rest assured as the Force is apparently strong with Disney, and they&amp;rsquo;ve created a brilliant space opera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like the original trilogy, “The Force Awakens” is a classic good versus bad story, but this time it’s fueled with exciting new characters, Rey (Daisy Ridley), Finn (John Boyega), and Poe (Oscar Isaac) alongside the iconic originals, Han Solo (Harrison Ford), Princess Leia (Carrie Fisher), and Luke Skywalker (Mark Hamill). The film takes place three decades after the events of “Return of the Jedi” and the familiar slanted word-scroll fills us in with the details of the past thirty years. In short: Luke Skywalker has vanished, and in his absence, the ashes of the old Empire have given birth to The First Order, a new threat to all peaceful systems and planets. It’s a race to see who can find Luke faster; the bad guys need to destroy the last Jedi knight, and the good guys need him to lead their side to victory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abrams tells the story with masterful pacing and balance. From action sequences to character development or sentimental drama to comic relief, the film never misses a beat. The plot is always driving forward, yet it seems to take its time traveling through the magnificent world that has been built, complete with its own eclectic mix of alien species and droids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seamless integration of new and old characters is a true testament to the success of the film. The new characters are never overshadowed by the old, and Ridley and Boyega have great chemistry with Ford, who acts as a sort of father figure while retaining the grumpy and irreverent attitude of Han Solo that fans have come to know and love. It’s safe to say that many viewers will walk out of the theater finding that while Luke, Han, and Leia still hold a special place in their hearts, they&amp;rsquo;ve also made room for the young Rey and Finn (and the adorable droid, BB-8).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the film isn’t perfect, but was perfection ever a feasibility? It certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t possible to please everybody. Some fans might be disappointed with the supposed power of the Dark Side, or the fact that the plot errs on the safe side. But for every &amp;ldquo;wrong&amp;rdquo;, there are ten more things that Abrams gets right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733; &amp;#9733;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: J.J. Abrams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starring: Daisy Ridley, John Boyega, Oscar Isaac, Adam Driver, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Mark Hamill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015, PG-13, 135 min&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#10084;&amp;#xFE0E; : Its the new characters that win over my heart. I can&#39;t wait to see how where the story will take Rey and Finn and how they will grow. I also tend to feel strongly movies when I admire the actors, and if Daisy Ridley keeps up the good work, she will join that small list of actors. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>