<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life Update on Kevin Li</title>
    <link>http://kevinwli.com/categories/life-update/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life Update on Kevin Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://kevinwli.com/categories/life-update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter: 3 Things I Learned</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2017-03-26-winter-3-things-I-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2017-03-26-winter-3-things-I-learned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spring break is almost over, and I’ve spent half of it alone in my apartment, cleaning, sleeping, and relaxing. While it’s not most people’s idea of a senior year spring break, it’s given me time to think about what’s happened to me so far this year. 2017 certainly came ready to fight, and I leave winter quarter with a fair share of bruises. It’s been a season of sadness and rejection, but it’s also been a season of tremendous growth and change, and I wanted to share a little bit about it. Here are 3 things I learned this quarter:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-how-to-disciple-others-when-i-don-t-always-have-the-right-answers-br-br&#34;&gt;1. How to disciple others when I don’t always have the right answers &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was asked during winter break if I was interested in discipling someone I was hesitant. “I’m just trying to figure things out for myself&amp;hellip; How can I possibly help guide others?” This thought has prevented me from applying for leadership roles in the past; I just didn’t think I was ready to lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I ended up saying yes, because while discipleship was something new to me, it was in a lot of ways, very familiar to me. As the eldest child of the family with two younger siblings, I’ve felt the pressure of being a good role-model since the day my brother was born. In the past, I’ve given young aspiring musicians lessons. And surprisingly, I’ve found that a lot of people come to me looking for relationship advice (this is unfortunately not a joke).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as I’ve gotten to know my disciples throughout winter quarter, I learned that discipleship isn’t about leading, walking in front, and telling them what’s right/wrong in life; it’s really about walking along side of them, listening, and growing together in this adventure called life, and it’s been one of the best experiences of my senior year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-how-to-be-alone-again-br-br&#34;&gt;2. How to be “alone” (again) &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or rather “how to deal with feelings of loneliness, bitterness, and anger”. Losing a relationship and seeing that connection collapse is often painful, and while it’s something that unfortunately happened to me, I’ve re-learned how to deal with these emotions and emerged from the experience with my head held high and ultimately much better than where I started a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do we deal with these ugly emotions? It’s a bit different for everyone; we all have our coping mechanisms. Some like to bottle up their emotions and put it on a high shelf, leaving it to fester until it explodes, potentially harming others around them. Others twist on the cap halfway, only letting a little bit of emotions come out at each time. And then there are people like me, who smash the bottle of emotions against the wall and face everything head on. I wouldn’t recommend the last one if you don’t have supportive friends or community to catch you when you fall. I call it my “safety net”. Without my safety net’s outpouring support, I’m not sure I would’ve recovered as quickly as I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People can surprise you when you’re grieving. A lot of people I wouldn’t expect came up to me and let me know they were here for me, available to talk, pray for me, etc. Honestly, it was quite touching, and it usually resulted in me excusing myself to the bathroom to wipe away the forming tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what I’m trying to say is I learned that I’m never truly alone, and that I’m so grateful for everyone who lifted me up this quarter. I know it’s cheesy, but y’all are a big part of the reason I’m doing well today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-how-to-let-go-of-what-i-cannot-control-br-br&#34;&gt;3. How to let go of what I cannot control &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t that long ago I would’ve been stressed out about not having an internship lined up for the summer by now, or that I’d be obsessing over what went wrong in my last interview when I thought everything went right. It wasn’t long ago that I couldn’t sleep at night because I was poring over every detail of my last relationship, trying to figure out what I could’ve done better. Yet today, I feel at peace with where I am, because I’ve learned to not worry about what I can’t control. It sounds so simple in practice, but for a people who are pseudo-perfectionists like myself, this can be difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not exactly sure what I did to finally feel this peace. Perhaps it was the meditative silence and solitude retreats I had almost every morning that calmed my mind. Perhaps it was using my new piano keyboard as a therapeutic tool. Perhaps it’s the encouragement I get from my friends, colleagues, and family that takes off a bit of the pressure. It was probably all three and more. It’s a realization that as much as we want to be in control, God is the one in control, and if we can’t even trust Him with something like our summer plans, how in the world are we going to trust Him with our salvation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I choose not to worry and to put my trust in Him. This doesn’t excuse me from trying my best in everything I do, but at least at the end of the day, I’ll have spent my energy in productive ways, and sleep easy knowing that He is good and that everything will be ok.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Best Moments of 2016</title>
      <link>http://kevinwli.com/post/2016-12-31-my-best-moments-of-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kevinwli.com/post/2016-12-31-my-best-moments-of-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The new year is just a few hours away, and it seems that 2016 will be forever seen as quite the poop stain on the scrolls of history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem fair to the good parts of 2016, and it&amp;rsquo;s no fun to be bombarded with bad news all the time. So instead of talking about the US election, Brexit, terrorist attacks, celebrity deaths, etc. I wanted to briefly share four of my favorite moments from this year. While reading about it might not be as interesting or uplifting to you as it was for me writing it, I hope that you can look back on your own year and see that maybe 2016 wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;winter&#34;&gt;WINTER&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;january-17-meeting-natalie&#34;&gt;January 17: Meeting Natalie&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/s--xxI2eAV---/c_scale,q_jpegmini:1,w_1600/v1483227922/IMG_0215_grthgq.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Natalie&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, this year was full of new friends and new experiences, and no other day better represents this than January 17th. I had just finished my first project for my film class, and I had a great time filming with some of my friends who graciously agreed to be my actors. After treating them to a fun dinner, I remembered that my other friend was holding her birthday party that night. While I wasn’t planning on going, I’m very glad I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the birthday party, I reconnected with many friends I hadn’t seen in a while, and I also met many new faces. Many of these new faces would go on to become my friends, but one face in particular caught my attention that night. You know those movie scenes where the guy sees the girl for the first time and he’s already in love? I always thought that was just a bunch of unrealistic crap, but I found myself in a similar movie scene that night when I met Natalie. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know it then, but in a little more than a month, this girl would be my girlfriend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;spring&#34;&gt;SPRING&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;may-29-my-brother-s-graduation&#34;&gt;May 29: My Brother’s Graduation&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/s--_drR7LkL--/c_scale,q_jpegmini:1,w_1600/v1483224613/IMG_1400_vsefej.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Michael&#39;s Graduation&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;
As the title suggests, my brother&amp;rsquo;s high school graduation was on this day, and it was hard to believe that he was already graduating when it felt like I had just graduated high school not too long ago. I came back home from school for that weekend to see him walk across the stage with a goofy graduation cap on. I didn’t come home alone though; Natalie and two of our good friends came as well to see my great homeland of Iowa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I know what you might be thinking: What is there to do in Iowa anyway? And you’d be mostly right if you thought the answer to that question was “nothing”. But experiences can be greatly enhanced by the people you are with, and this day was no exception. After attending the graduation ceremony and embarrassing my brother as he walked across the stage, my friends and I took a trip up to the Maquoketa Caves and hiked around. We had dinner at this awesome all-you-can-eat fried chicken and shrimp place, and went to the drive-in theatre afterwards to watch X-Men Apocalypse (I don’t recommend the movie by the way). It was the most fun I had in the state of Iowa in recent memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summer&#34;&gt;SUMMER&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;june-10-16-banff&#34;&gt;June 10-16: Banff&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/s--K8bd-hwu--/c_scale,q_jpegmini:1,w_1600/v1483224427/IMG_1970_lhdlwj.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Banff&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;
Shortly after the school year ended, I flew out to Banff, Canada to meet up with my family and explore the Canadian Rockies. Banff has been on my &amp;ldquo;bucket list&amp;rdquo; of travel destinations, so I was super excited to experience it. Banff is just as beautiful as everyone says it is, and spending time with family was good after a hard quarter of classes. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a 2017 free pass to all of the Canadian national parks, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be definitely looking for another opportunity to go back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fall&#34;&gt;FALL&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;september-15-18-disney-universal&#34;&gt;September 15-18: Disney &amp;amp; Universal&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/s--F9wkX7Pr--/c_scale,q_jpegmini:1,w_1600/v1483228147/2016-09-16_11.46.16_exixx8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Disney&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;
(They always seem to be doing construction on that castle&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right before going back to school, Natalie and her brother and I took a trip out to Orlando to visit Disney World’s Magic Kingdom and Universal Studio’s Harry Potter World. Now I’ve been to these places before, but of course, things are different when you’re going with your significant other. The whole experience was pretty surreal, and I loved watching Natalie react to all the cool, wonderful stuff in Harry Potter World and just feel like a little kid again. Plus, it was good to relax and get away from home after an eleven-week internship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;winter-1&#34;&gt;WINTER&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;reflection&#34;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/lilingkai/image/upload/s--HvvO9Pff--/c_scale,q_jpegmini:1,w_1600/v1480470080/typewriter_bbq4uv.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Reflection&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto; witdth: auto\9; /* ie8 */&#34;&gt;
2016 has been a transformative year for me, and while you could say that technically every year has been transformative, I&amp;rsquo;d say it&amp;rsquo;s doubly true for 2016. I&amp;rsquo;ve made so many new friends, gotten involved with the Christian Asian American community on campus, filmed a documentary and short film, wrote a TV-show script, learned about machine learning and other new technologies, sang in a church choir, and traveled to new and old destinations with fresh eyes. The biggest things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about myself is that I really value strong communities and relationships. I hope that next year I can keep strengthening the communities and relationships I&amp;rsquo;m already a part of, as well as cultivating new ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of next year, I can say that 2017 will be even more transformative: graduating college, becoming a &amp;ldquo;real adult&amp;rdquo;, and finding a job is going to be one helluva ride, and I&amp;rsquo;d be lying if I said I wasn&amp;rsquo;t a little scared. But you bet I&amp;rsquo;ll be ready for whatever is coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy new year everybody. I&amp;rsquo;ll see you on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>